The new morning we've finally found
Yatto mitsuketa atarashii asa wa
is being hampered by the past.
Tsukihi ga jama wo suru
What we chased after wasn't the future,
Mukau saki wa tsugi ja nakute
but the past so full of remorse.
Sugi bakari oikaketa
The ruthless memories won't stop playing;
Nariyamanai yousha nai omoide tachi wa
they won't be forgiving us for a long time.
Yurushite kuresou nimonai
It's about now that a teardrop
Sorosoro kana tesaguri tsukareta hoho wo
beings to roll down my fatigued cheeks.
Kattou ga koboreochiru
Will this rain ever stop?
Ame wa itsuka yamunodeshouka
I've been freezing for a long time.
Zuibun nagai aida tsumetai
Why does the rain continue to fix on me?
Ame wa doushite boku wo erabuno
I wonder if it could embrace me.
Tsutsumarete iikana
Today, the rain falls again;
Ame wa yamu koto wo shirazuni
endlessly it falls knowing no end.
Kyou mo furitsuzukukeredo
We nestle close to each other to share the warmth
Sotto sashidashita kasa no naka de
under this umbrella, you gently held out to me.
Nukumori ni yorisoinagara
Fullmetal!
He disappeared?!
What did you do?!
He was simply escorted to a place
you'll eventually arrive at yourself.
What the hell is this?
This sensation...
That's right!
The same sensation I got when I opened the Gate of Truth!
Sacrifices
Dammit!
You son of a bitch!
You're...!
Idiot!
Leave this place to us!
It's our duty...
...to protect the young master.
It's impossible to carry this much weight with an automail!
Worry about your grandfather instead!
It's...
...too late.
Briggs soldiers, lend me a hand!
Right!
Bradley, eat this!
Fu!
Fu!!
Someone call a doctor!
Are there any doctors well-versed in alchemy?!
I've...
I've got a philosopher's stone right here!
Use as much of it as you need!
Anyone!
Please!
Isn't Amestris the land of alchemy?!
There's gotta be someone here!
Hey!!
Why...?
Why...
Young master!
You monster...
Why...
I can't save a single vassal despite achieving immortality...?
Fuck!!
Captain!
Captain, get yourself together!
Captain!!
Fire!
We were able to give Bradley a fatal wound thanks to you.
Even though you ensured that Fu's death would not be in vain,
I can't even do a thing to help you.
Give me ammo!
That was the last round!
Shit!
I'm out too!
Everyone, fire back with your rifles!
Roger!
Lin Yao...
Or Greed, whichever you are...
If you're truly thankful, would you mind doing me a favor?
We're not supposed to let this gate open until our Queen orders it to be.
Please, protect it...
It should be possible with your strength...
No, only you... can do it...
I'm begging you...
Greed.
Yo?
I want power.
Lend me some.
Sure thing.
We've still got some time until my next plan.
Lan Fan, you protect the people here.
Roger!
Could you... do that for me?
Yeah, I promise.
People from Xing...
...never break alliances!
Fire! Fire!
W-Who the hell is that?!
All right, listen up!
Those who don't wish to get hurt,
and those who have family and lovers, stand back!
And women, too!
I don't particularly enjoy fighting women!
No way...!
Fire!!
Incredible...
Lin Yao.
Or should I say, Homunculus?
How promising they are once you have one on your side...
Captain!
Captain, please hang in there!
Did he... join our side?
Yes, sir!
Now I can kick the bucket in peace...
What are you saying, Captain?!
Major General Armstrong will achieve victory soon!
Just a little longer!
We need you to take an even more active role in Central than ever before!
I don't like the sooty sky here in Central...
Farewell, comrades...
I'll go on ahead...
...to an even higher place than the summit of Briggs...
Captain Buccaneer!!!
What was that flash of light from before?
There hasn't been a single announcement.
What's going on with military headquarters?
No follow-up reports from Radio Capital?
Nope.
What about the other stations?
They're just announcing a curfew for the moment.
Mommy!
The radio tells us we can't go outside,
so let's hold off on going to Tabasa's house today, okay, Elicia?
What?!
We can see the solar eclipse from here, too.
It's about to begin,
so let's watch it from here with Mommy.
Izumi!
Where are you?!
Izumi!!
Alex, do you know what just happened?
I heard this from the Elric Brothers in the past.
They said that when they performed human transmutation,
they were dragged into the Gate of Truth by black hands.
What is this "Gate of Truth" you speak of?
I have no idea.
What did you say?!
Were you able to get in touch with them?
Major General, headquarters is safe.
Good.
And, did you obtain any information pertaining to Miss Izumi's situation?
No...
I see...
And what else?
During a battle with King Bradley,
Captain Buccaneer, who was defending the main gate,
lost his life along with a few other men.
It has been reported that the captain,
working together with someone from Xing,
successfully gave Bradley a fatal wound and knocked him down into a canal.
Impossible!
There's no way that can be true!
How could that King Bradley die so easily?!
He's not human-
And what about the main gate?
It's still being defended.
A homunculus by the name of Greed joined their side,
and tore apart the central soldiers at the main gate.
A homunculus?!
Impossible.
A homunculus would never turn its fangs on that man...
Apparently, Captain Buccaneer passed away with a smile.
I see.
If he died with a smile, we can't sit here and weep.
Let's proceed!
Roger!
Let's go, Mr. Sig.
We also need to look for your wife.
Right.
Ouch...
Oww...
Master!
Ed!
Are you okay?!
Yeah, somewhat.
What are you doing here?
That's what I want to know.
So, where are we?
I don't know.
I was just sent here all of a sudden...
Al!
Hey!
Even Al?
Get yourself together!
Could it be that all the human sacrifices were gathered?
What's wrong, Al?!
Hey!
One, two, three...
...and four.
We're missing one.
I guess the last one is currently being made.
W-What the hell is this monster?
Hohenheim!
Edward...
Even Alphonse was captured...?
Whoa, Miss Izumi as well.
Sorry I'm in such a pitiful state.
What in the world is going on?
Well...
You stay put.
I'll slowly absorb the philosopher's stone inside you later.
Who the hell is that dark guy, Hohenheim?!
My alter ego.
The guy who the homunculi called 'Father'.
That's the geezer?!
Yeah.
I was able to destroy his skin, but...
Quit your blabbering, Hohenheim.
I welcome you, human sacrifices.
Thanks for coming to my castle.
Al, wake up.
This one's going to be tough.
Al?
Hey, Al!
Alphonse!
The ones up there are so unreliable.
They couldn't even prepare five human sacrifices for this day?
Well, I gathered all the ones who've been seeking morsels like immortality,
so it's no surprise that they couldn't do their jobs.
Damn you!
Excellent. Stay just like that.
Now, Mustang, we don't have much time.
I'd appreciate it if you could willingly cooperate with me.
Do you mind performing human transmutation and opening the gate?
What?
I don't care who you transmutate.
Your late parents, your lover, your friend.
The one you were close to...
What was his name again?
Hughes.
I don't mind if you transmutate him.
We'll take care of all the arrangements.
The ones you call... "human sacrifices"?
Precisely.
Those who open the gate can become human sacrifices.
So that's why the Elric Brothers were chosen.
Yup.
I heard from them that human transmutation doesn't work.
What idiot would try it when they know it's not going to work?!
Good point there.
So as long as you open the gate and come back, it's fine.
I refuse!
I won't perform human transmutation!
I won't open the gate either!
Didn't I tell you that we don't have much time?
Lieutenant!
Lieutenant?!
Now, open the gate, Mustang.
You scum!!
Lieutenant! Can you hear me?!
Say something!
Now, perform human transmutation and become the fifth sacrifice.
Come on, if you don't pick up the pace, this woman will die.
Oh, I get it.
You're going to transmute her back after she dies?
That's fine too.
I won't die...
I've been ordered not to die...
If one could obtain an immortal body with an order like that,
everyone would live without worry.
What will you do, Mustang?
A woman who's precious to you is dying.
If you leave her be, she'll die from blood loss.
But I'm a doctor well-versed in alchemy,
and tadaa, I even have a philosopher's stone.
In other words, I can save this woman's life.
Well, if she dies before you make a decision, there'll be nothing I can do.
Oh?
She's gotten quiet.
I wonder if she died.
Colonel...
There's no need... for you to perform human transmutation.
You'll do it, won't you, Mustang?
Now!
I will.
Ever since that day passed,
Ano hi kara zutto
I promised myself that I'd never cry.
Nakanaito kimetekitakedo
But even while I hoarded up the pain,
Itami wo kasanetemo
there was something I couldn't forgive myself for.
Nanika wo yurusezu ni ita
I'll never be able
Mou modorenai
to return to those days.
Ikutsumo no hibi
I'm still powerless.
Boku wa mada nanimo dekizuni
I watch as the shards of memories disappear, one by one;
Kimi no ita kioku no kakera
memories of when you were still with me.
Mata hitotsu kieteyuku
I long to become
Kyou yori motto
stronger than I am now,
Tsuyoku naritai
so that my voice will eventually reach you.
Kono koe ga itsuka todokuyouni
If the wind happens to stop
Arukitsuzukete
in the midst of my long journey,
Kaze ga yandara
I'll look up at the sky in search of you.
Kimi wo sagashite sora miageruyo
Beyond the daybreak, a ray of light breaks free.
Yoake no saki ni hikari ga sasuyo
A rainbow spans across the sky.
Niji ga kakaruyo
Though there may be favorable turn,
know that this repose last but a moment.
The place upon which thou standest is the entrance to the netherworld.
Next time, Fullmetal Alchemist:
Episode 59, Lost Light.
Lost Light
The end is near.